IBRAHIMABDULSALAMI

LUTON | ibrahimdele@hotmail.com | 07516428921

PERSONAL STATEMENT

A passionate Cloud Engineer, experienced in windows administration, incident management, virtualization, automation, deploying and configuring cloud solutions to ensure production environments are secure and reliable. Able to adapt to new environments and grasp concepts quickly, with a strong desire to build upon existing skillset. My career goal is to work with a dynamic firm in an environment competitive enough to provide challenges capable of harnessing my potentials towards the attainment of organizational objectives.

EDUCATION

MSc Project Management | University of Hertfordshire | 2013 – 2014 BEng Electronic/Electrical Engineering | University of Hertfordshire | 2010 – 2013

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

- ITIL® Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Working with Microsoft Azure SQL Skillsoft

WORK EXPERIENCE

TSYS (2021 – Present)

Technical Support Analyst II

- Provided technical support and responding to variety of complex technical issues, service requests, incidents and change requests from clients experiencing issues with their networking, applications, and virtualization across the IT infrastructure.
- Projects worked on: SmartCX project, Laptop refresh, TSYS Hamburg call center implementation
- Ensured that iGEL thin Clients and Virtual Desktop Infrastructure (VDI) devices interconnect seamlessly with file servers and mail servers.
- Office 365, Azure AD and Active Directory administration
- Exchange 2013 / Exchange online administration

- Performed routine virtual desktop maintenance (VDI patching, image maintenance, applications, and server upgrades)
- Administered and maintained group policy objects.
- Vulnerability remediation
- IT Asset management
- Developed and demonstrated expertise in Powershell scripting to automate routine tasks, such as onboarding new starters and etc.
- Basic knowledge of Azure Function Apps and Power Automate to optimize workflow processes, reducing manual interventions.
- Maintained meticulous documentation and project records, ensuring efficient project management and knowledge sharing.
- Managed the kit installation and VDI imaging for TSYS Hamburg call center project resulting in 100% successful go live experience.

DOMINOS PIZZA

(2018 - 2021)

Senior IT Support Analyst

- Managed the 1st line analysts using agile to ensure requests and incidents are prioritized and actioned effectively.
- Experienced in using Veam software for data back up and restoration.
- Demonstrated ISO27001 awareness by adhering to security best practices, ensuring data confidentiality and integrity in compliance with industry standards.
- Liaising with third party vendors to manage incident and ensure they are resolved within the SLA.
- Leveraged Azure operational experience to design, implement, and maintain cloudbased solutions
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams working with Dynamics 365 to enhance web content management.
- Experienced in using SQL for data management. Writing and executing SQL queries in SQL database.
- Analyzing and creating reports via Tableau, Excel, SSRS etc
- VPN, O365, Azure AD and Active Directory administration. Provided access and permissions using Azure RBAC
- Utilized Azure Monitor and Application Insights to continuously monitor and optimize application performance, resulting in 99.9% uptime.
- Exchange 2013 / Exchange online, and Windows Server 2012 administration
- Administration and monitoring of network virtualization equipment Cisco router, Meraki

FUJITSU (2016 - 2018)

IT Support Engineer

• Provided technical support via telephone and remotely resolving hardware/software issues.

- Managed customer queries using ServiceNow to log and monitor issues.
- Provided support with Windows 7, Windows 10 and Office 365
- Active directory; user and computer management.

PROJECTS AND HANDS-ON EXPERIENCE

- Automation of Azure AD Users creation using Logic Apps.
- Cloud detection project using Microsoft Defender, Microsoft Sentinel, Azure Monitor and Kusto Query Language.
- Deployed IaaS and PaaS solutions with Azure SQL
- Comprehensive Azure monitoring and remediation solution project
- Administered Azure relational database solution
- Backup and Disaster recovery using Azure Backup and Azure Site Recovery

TECHNICAL AND SOFT SKILLS

- Programming/Scripting SQL, PowerShell, Azure CLI
- Virtualization VMware, Hyper-V, VDI, VMware Horizon
- Operating System Windows, Linux
- Project Management
- Networking DHCP, TCP/IP, Cisco Meraki
- Server Management Windows Server 2008 2012, Exchange Server
- Administration Active Directory, Azure AD, Exchange Online, Group Policy, SharePoint, Teams, OneDrive
- Azure cloud services Azure Storage, Azure SQL, VM, Azure Data Factory, Azure Synapse Analytics, Azure Networking, Azure Logic Apps, Azure Functions. Azure App Service.
- Infrastructure as code Azure ARM, Terraform, Bicep
- Tools Visual Studio Code and Azure Data Studio
- Data Visualization Tableau and Power BI
- Soft Skills Attention to detail, collaboration, communication, great work ethic, problem solving, time management, positive mindset, creativity, decision making